Finding Aid for the Will Connell Papers LSC.0893
UCLA Library Special Collections
Will Connell papers
1928-1961
UCLA Library Special Collections
Connell, Will
LSC.0893
76.0 linear feet (152 boxes)
Will Connell (1898-1961) was a self-taught photographer. He opened a studio in downtown Los Angeles in 1925 and became a member of the Camera Pictorialists. He taught at Art Center College in Pasadena from 1931 until his death. His work included movie publicity shots, magazine assignments and other commercial photography. The collection consists of photographs, negatives, experimental work, correspondence, instructional materials, and ephemera.
Conditions Governing Access
Open for research. All requests to access special collections materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
PORTIONS OF THIS COLLECTION HAVE BEEN DIGITIZED. Please consult digital facsimiles instead of originals.
Provenance/Source of Acquisition
Gift of Grace Connell and Will Connell, Jr., 1964-1966.
UCLA Catalog Record ID
UCLA Catalog Record ID: 9942329023606533
Missing Material
(Box 1 Missing October 1990)
Biography
Connell was born in 1898 in McPherson, Kansas; came with mother to California, and attended Los Angeles High School; left in the tenth grade to enlist in the army, but World War I had ended; became a pharmacist; in the 1920s taught himself photography, and opened a studio in downtown Los Angeles in 1925; became a member of the Camera Pictorialists along with Edward Weston, Louis Fleckenstein, and others; taught at Art Center College in Pasadena from 1931 until his death; work also included movie publicity shots, magazine assignments and other commercial photography; was one of the first photojournalists, illustrating numerous articles for Colliers and The Saturday Evening Post; wrote long-running column in U.S. Camera called Counsel by Connell; produced three photography books: In Pictures (1931), The Missions of California (1941), and About Photography (1949); he died in 1961.
Biographical / Historical
Will Connell was born in McPherson, Kansas in 1898. His father, a cowpuncher, kept moving the family westward and ultimately left them in Portland, Oregon. Mrs. Connell, a school teacher, relocated to Los Angeles where Will, an only child, went to Los Angeles High School. In 10th grade, Will dropped out of school to join the Army, but World War I came to an end and spoiled his plans. He then had a variety of jobs from soda-jerk to pharmacist, a job for which he had to obtain a pharmacy license, which he updated with pride throughout his life.
In the 1920s, Connell became a self-taught photographer, learning on a four-by-five camera. In 1925, he opened a studio on Seventh Street in downtown Los Angeles and started to exhibit in Pictorialist exhibits with good success. He was a member of the Camera Pictorialists along with Edward Weston, Louis Fleckenstein, and others. He was also a member of a group of prominent Los Angelenos who met regularly at Jake Zeitlin's bookshop. They included Merle Armitage, Paul Jordan Smith, Phil Townsend Hanna, Lloyd Wright, Cary McWilliams, and Lawrence Tippet.
In 1931, Connell started a thirty year teaching career at Art Center College of Design that ended with his death in 1961. He was a dedicated teacher and held weekly meetings at his home for his students which always turned into lively discussions. Connell married a student of his, Grace Allen, and she stabilized his heretofore bohemian life by giving him a home and family: Will, Jr. (1935) and Samantha (1938). Will closed his downtown studio and worked out of a home office / studio. His work, in addition to teaching nights, now included publicity shots for the movie studios, magazine work, and various types of cormercial photography such as Sunkist ads, jewelry and fashion advertising for stores like Bullock's Wilshire, and industrial views for technical brochures, such as Kaiser Steel Mills in Fontana, California. He was one of the first photojournalists, and illustrated numerous articles for Colliers and The Saturday Evening Post. Not only did Connell provide pictures for magazines, for 15 years he also turned out a monthly column for U.S. Camera entitled Counsel by Connell. It was a very popular technical question and answer column done in an informal, humorous way. In addition to all his other work, Connell produced three photography books: In Pictures (1931), The Missions of California (1941), and About Photography (1949).
The UCLA holdings reflect all of Will Connell's work, and span his entire career.
Kayla Landesman
Scope and Content
Collection consists of photographs, negatives, experimental work, correspondence, instructional materials, and ephemera. Most of the photographs were taken in Los Angeles and vicinity.
Online Items Available
Portions of this collection have been digitized and are available online: Will Connell papers (502 items).
Negatives (photographs).; Photographs.; Commercial photography -- California, Southern.; Photographers -- California -- Los Angeles -- Archives.; Art Center College of Design (Pasadena, Calif.)--Faculty--Archives.; Connell, Will, 1898-1961--Archives.; Art Center College of Design (Pasadena, Calif.)
- Salon Prints of Movie Stars, (1 Box of 45 × 35cm., unless otherwise noted)
  - 1. George Arliss, 1938. (Box 1)
  - 2. George Arliss, 1934. (Box 1)
  - 3. George Arliss, 1932. (Box 1)
    General note
    This photograph is now in the possession of Will Connell Jr.
  - 4. Sallie Blaine, 1931. (Box 1)
  - 5. Sallie Blaine, 1932. (Box 1)
  - 6. Sallie Blaine, 1931. (Box 1)
  - 7. Mary Brian, 1932. (Box 1)
  - 8. Mary Brian, 1932. (Box 1)
  - 9. Mary Brian, 1932. (Box 1)
  - 10. Constance Cummings, 1933. (Box 1)
  - 11. Constance Cummings, 1931. (Box 1)
  - 12. Walt Disney, n.d. (Box 1)
  - 13. Walt Disney, n.d.; (Duplicate of no.12). (Box 1)
  - 14. Walt Disney, 1935. (Box 1)
  - 15. W.C. Fields, n.d. (Box 1)
  - 16. Sydney Fox, 1932. (Box 1)
  - 17. Sydney Fox, 1932. (Box 1)
  - 18. Jean Harlow, 1931. (Box 1)
  - 19. Myrna Loy, 1932. (Box 1)
  - 20. Myrna Loy, 1932.; (Duplicate of no.19). (Box 1)
  - 21. Lon Nora, 1939. (Box 1)
  - 22. Ginger Rogers, n.d. (Box 1)
  - 23. Ginger Rogers, 1931. (Box 1)
  - 24. Ginger Rogers, 1932. (Box 1)
  - 25. Ginger Rogers, 1932.; (Duplicate of no.24) Smaller: 24.5 × 19cm. (Box 1)
  - 26. Ginger Rogers, 1932. (Box 1)
  - 27. Barbara Weeks, 1931. (Box 1)
  - 28. Barbara Weeks, (Apparent duplicate of no.29, despite discrepancy of dates)., 1931. (Box 1)
  - 29. Barbara Weeks, 1930. (Box 1)
  - 30. Pat O'Brian, n.d.; (21 × 26cm.). (Box 1)
  - 31. Pat O'Brian, n.d.; (21 × 26cm.). (Box 1)
- Factory View. Also: Advertisement Photographs, (Mounted, 45 × 35cm, unless otherwise noted); Box 2
  - 1. South Arkansas no.129, n.d. (Box 2)
  - 2. Trona, 1928. (Box 2)
  - 3. Merco valves at Tima, 1930. (Box 2)
  - 4. Trona, 1928. (Box 2)
  - 5. Trona (?), 1929. (Box 2)
  - 6. Untitled photograph of pylon, 1931. (Box 2)
  - 7. Untitled photograph of machine part, 1929. (Box 2)
  - 8. Untitled photograph of machine parts, n.d. (Box 2)
  - 9. Untitled photograph of rods, n.d. (Box 2)
  - 10. Motor-shafting at U.S. Motors, 1928. (Box 2)
  - 11. Oil pump parts, 1931. (Box 2)
  - 12. The Welder, 1930. (Box 2)
  - 13. The Iron Alligator, 1930. (Box 2)
  - 14. Arc Welding, n.d. (Box 2)
  - 15. Untitled photograph of men hammering stakes, 1928. (Box 2)
  - 16. Gyratory grinding, 1929. (Box 2)
  - 17. Gyratory grinding, 1928. (Box 2)
  - 18. Pulling the slag, n.d. (Box 2)
  - 19. Dynamometer test, 1928. (Box 2)
  - 20. Milling operation, 1920 (?). (Box 2)
  - 21. Heat treating, 1930. (Box 2)
  - 22. Testing micrometer, 1928. (Box 2)
  - 23. Untitled photograph of researcher using microscope, n.d. (Box 2)
  - 24. Untitled photograph of maching parts (?), 1930. (Box 2)
  - 25. Assembly line, Douglas plant, 1936. (Box 2)
  - 26. Douglas plant, 1936. (Box 2)
  - 27. Wings, 1936. (Box 2)
  - 28. Douglas Aircraft plant, 1936.; (Duplicate of no.26 and 27, different title). (Box 2)
  - 29. Douglas plant, 1936. (Box 2)
  - 30. Bodies on the line, 1937.; (Duplicate of no.25, different title). (Box 2)
  - 31. Untitled photograph of airplane with propellers in motion, 1930. (Box 2)
  - 32. Cal Ship, World War II, n.d. (Box 2)
  - 33. Untitled photograph of stacks of lumber, 1943. (Box 2)
  - 34. Torch cutting slots, 1949. (Box 2)
  - 35. no.21, 1950. (Box 2)
  - 36. Thread gage, n.d. (Box 2)
  - 37-38. Mens wear ads, 1931.; (2 photos, different poses). (Box 2)
  - 39. Unidentified woman on sofa, 1932.; Special effect printing. (Box 2)
  - 40. Modesty Forbids, Hosiery ad(?)., 1935(?); Trick photography. (Box 2)
  - 41. Fighter and Letters-to-the-Editor, 1938.; Trick photography. (Box 2)
  - 42-43. Study for a head in the hand, 1933.; Trick photography (2 copies, no.25 untitled). (Box 2)
  - 44. All-year Club, Montage promoting Southern California/Los Angeles., 1937. (Box 2)
  - 45-47. Savabrush ads, n.d.; (no.27-28 duplicates, unmounted 43 × 35cm.; no.29 mounted, 35 × 43cm.). (Box 2)
  - 48-49. Print of stripes, Trick effect., 1930.; (2 copies; no.30 unmounted 36 × 28cm.). (Box 2)
  - 50. Untitled photograph of hands and test tubes, Trick effect: two photos mounted as one. (Box 2)
- Nursery School Book, 1943. (Box 3)
  - Photographs of nursery-school children. Also included is 1 book of tissue mock-ups., 27 cardboard mounts, 37 × 59cm. (Box 3)
    (See Box 1 for text)
- Views of San Francisco, railroad trains, and California Missions. Also Beach scenes, 1929-1935.; Mounted photographs, mainly 45 × 35cm. (Box 4)
  - 1-5. Golden Gate Bridge scenes, San Francisco, 1937. (Box 4)
    - 1. Eddy. (Box 4)
    - 2. Victorian Vestige. (Box 4)
    - 3. Perspective. (Box 4)
    - 4. Sodium lamp. (Box 4)
      Photograph removed, now in Box 36.
    - 5. Golden Gate Bridge. (Box 4)
  - 6. San Francisco, (aerial view)., n.d. (Box 4)
  - 7. Mt. San Jacinto -, early 1930s. (Box 4)
  - 8-10. Unidentified photograph of trains in the San Bernardino roundhouse (Box 4)
    One photograph removed, now in Box 36.
  - 11. Untitled photograph of train, n.p., n.d. (Box 4)
  - 12. Untitled photograph of train, n.p., 1929. (Box 4)
  - 13. The Six-fifteen, n.p., 1929. (Box 4)
  - 14. Pressure, 1936. (Box 4)
  - 15. Heat, or, Colton, 1937. (Box 4)
  - 16. Colton, 1937.; (Duplicate of no.15, enlarged print). (Box 4)
  - 17. Heat, 1937.; (Duplicate of no.15 and 16, different title). (Box 4)
  - 18. Bell Tower, Pala Mission, n.d.; (Unmounted). (Box 4)
  - 19-20. Interior of Corridor, San Fernando Mission, (Unmounted, duplicate photos). (Box 4)
  - 21. San Juan Bautista plaza scene, 1929. (Box 4)
  - 22. South Facade, Mission Santa Barbara, 1929. (Box 4)
  - 23. Mission Santa Barbara, 1932. (Box 4)
  - 24. East Bell Tower, Mission Santa Barbara, 1929. (Box 4)
  - 25-26. Detail of West Bell Tower, Mission Santa Barbara, 1932.; (Duplicate photos). (Box 4)
  - 27. Mission Santa Barbara, 1929. (Box 4)
  - 28. East Main Facade, Mission San Gabriel Archangel, 1933. (Box 4)
  - 29. San Juan Capistrano, 1929. (Box 4)
  - 30. View from the Plaza, Mission San Juan Bautista, 1929. (Box 4)
  - 31. San Juan Bautista, n.d. (Box 4)
  - 32-57. 25 cardboard mounts, mainly 45 × 35cm. Photographs of beaches, sunbathers, etc. Unidentified, but chiefly Santa Monica, California. (Box 4)
- Water scenes. Mounted photographs. Chiefly California beach views., (45 × 35cm.). (Box 5)
- Untitled salon prints. Advertisement photographs., (45 × 35cm.). (Box 5)
- Salon Prints of Taos, Santa Fe and Portraits, All Dated 1932; (Mounted, 45 × 35 cm., unless otherwise noted)
  - 1-2. Southern spit of Balboa Bay, 1935.; (Duplicate photographs). (Box 5)
  - 3. Balboa, 1932. (Box 5)
  - 4. Santa Barbara, n.d. (Box 5)
  - 5. Casino at Avalon (Catalina Island) (Box 5)
  - 6. Avalon, 1934. (Box 5)
  - 7. Avalon, 1934. (Box 5)
  - 8. On the Malibu, 1928. (Box 5)
  - 9. Sunset hour; coast at foot of Topanga Canyon, 1934. (Box 5)
  - 10. Unidentified photograph, 1921.; (Apparent duplicate of no.9, despite discrepancy of dates; smaller: 9.8 × 12.2cm.). (Box 5)
  - 11. Fisherman's yarns, 1929. (Box 5)
  - 12. Sunset, 1926. (Box 5)
  - 13. Unidentified photograph of tanker ship near shore, n.d. (Box 5)
  - 14. Unidentified photograph of swimming pool, 1929. (Box 5)
  - 15. Unidentified photograph of swimming pool, 1930. (Box 5)
  - 16-20. Jewelry. (Box 5)
    - 16. Earrings and pin, 1929. (Box 5)
    - 17. Watches, necklace, and pin, 1929. (Box 5)
    - 18-19. Pins, rings, and necklaces, 1929.; (2 copies, no.4 enlarged). (Box 5)
    - 20. Ornate necklace, 1929. (Box 5)
  - 21. Plaid blanket on bed, n.d. (Box 5)
  - 22-28. Men's clothing. (Box 5)
    - 22. Male in overcoat, scarf and hat (Box 5)
    - 23. Necktie and fabric swatches, 1931. (Box 5)
    - 24. Fedora on spring fashion catalog, 1929. (Box 5)
    - 25. Fedora by vase of pussy willows, 1929. (Box 5)
    - 26. Oxfords on a braided rug, 1928. (Box 5)
    - 27. Oxfords, 1930. (Box 5)
    - 28. Business executive in pinstriped suit, n.d. (Box 5)
  - 29-31. Hands, 1931-32.; (2 poses, no.15 and 16, duplicates). (Box 5)
  - 32-35. Decorative objects. (Box 5)
    - 32. Wine goblet, 1936. (Box 5)
    - 33. Glass flamincos and vase, 1930. (Box 5)
    - 34. Vases, 1929. (Box 5)
    - 35. Metal vase on fabric, 1930. (Box 5)
  - 36. Dentist viewing X-rays, n.d. (Box 5)
  - 37. Dentist drilling cavity, n.d. (Box 5)
  - 38. Boxing glove in action, n.d. (Box 5)
  - 39. Two pairs of oxfords - baby and adult (Box 5)
  - 40-49. Taos, New Mexico., Unmounted photographs. (Box 5)
    - 40. Entrance to the Kiras, Taos., (19.5 × 24.5cm.). (Box 5)
    - 41. Taos., (20 × 25cm.). (Box 5)
    - 42-48. Church at Ranchos de Taos, various views., (20 × 25cm.). (Box 5)
    - 49. Taos., (20 × 25cm.). (Box 5)
  - 50. Taos Pueblo, Taos. (Box 5)
  - 51-58. Santa Fe, New Mexico. (Box 5)
    - 51-53. Corpus Christi parade, various views., (Unmounted, 19.5 × 25cm.). (Box 5)
    - 54. Corpus Christi - The Sena Shrine. (Box 5)
    - 55. Corpus Christi, leaving the St. Francis Cathedral (view from opposite cathedral). (Box 5)
    - 56. Untitled view of Corpus Christi., (Unmounted, 20 × 25cm.). (Box 5)
    - 57-58. Cathedral of St. Francis., (2 views). (Box 5)
  - 59. Montage of churches (California missions)., (24 × 48.5cm.). (Box 5)
- Salon prints of the oil industry - fields and refineries., Mounted (45 × 35cm.) unless noted. (Box 6)
- Portraits, all, dated 1932.; (Mounted (45 × 35cm.) unless otherwise noted). (Box 6)
  - 1. Union Oil at San Pedro, 1931. (Box 6)
  - 2. 335. Standard Refinery, Kettleman [California], 1931. (Box 6)
  - 3. Untitled. Close-up of valves, 1931. (Box 6)
  - 4. Standard Oil Refinery in Kettleman Hills [California], 1931. (Box 6)
  - 5. Untitled. Close-up of pipes, 1931. (Box 6)
  - 6. Gas separation plant, 1931. (Box 6)
  - 7. Union Oil Refinery, n.d.; (Unmounted, 26 × 46cm.). (Box 6)
  - 8. Lorraine (?) towers at Standard well in the North dome, Kettleman Hills [California] field, 1931. (Box 6)
  - 9. Gas compression plant, 1931. (Box 6)
  - 10-11. Valves, 1930.; (2 copies). (Box 6)
  - 12. Untitled. Close-up of valves, 1931. (Box 6)
  - 13. Diaphragm valves, 1930. (Box 6)
  - 14. Boiler fuel pumps, 1930. (Box 6)
  - 15. Untitled. Close-up of pipes, 1931. (Box 6)
  - 16. Refinery, 1931. (Box 6)
    Photograph removed, now in Box 37.
  - 17. Untitled. Close-up of pipes, n.d. (Box 6)
  - 18. Untitled. Refinery with oil derricks in background. (Box 6)
  - 19. Untitled. Close-up of smoke polluting air at the oil derricks, n.d. (Box 6)
  - 20. Untitled. Refinery in front of oil derricks, 1930. (Box 6)
  - 21. Untitled. Oil derricks, 1930. (Box 6)
  - 22. Untitled. Field of oil derricks, 1930. (Box 6)
  - 23. Union Oil - Sante Fe, 1930. (Box 6)
  - 24. Gas compression plant, 1931. (Box 6)
  - 25. Untitled. Close-up of oil derrick, 1931. (Box 6)
  - 26. Standard Oil, Kettleman [California], 1931. (Box 6)
  - 27-28. Untitled. Close-up of valves releasing steam, 1931.; (2 copies). (Box 6)
  - 29. Untitled. Valves releasing steam, derricks in background, 1931. (Box 6)
  - 30-32. Untitled. Close-up of valves releasing steam, viewed through pipes, 1931-32.; (3 copies, apparent duplicates despite discrepancy of dates; no.31 glossy finish). (Box 6)
  - 33-34. Untitled. View from top of derrick, looking down it's interior, n.d.; (2 copies). (Box 6)
  - (1) 35-38. Drilling rig, 1931.; (Various views; no.35 and 36 are duplicates). (Box 6)
    These photographs are now in the possession of Will Connell Jr.
  - 39. Untitled. Field of derricks, 1931. (Box 6)
  - 40. Untitled. Men at oil well pump, n.d. (Box 6)
  - 41. Untitled. Pool of oil and mud near drilling rig, 1930. (Box 6)
  - 42. Sump, 1931. (Box 6)
  - 43. Oil sump, 1931.; (Matted). (Box 6)
  - 44-63. Portraits. (Box 6)
    - 44. Joseph Henry Sharp., (Unmounted, 20 × 25cm.). (Box 6)
    - 45. Kenneth M. Adams., (Unmounted, 20 × 25cm.). (Box 6)
    - 46. Dr. Martin(?)., (Unmounted, 20 × 25cm.). (Box 6)
    - (2) 47-50. John Dunn., (Unmounted, 20 × 12cm; unmounted 35.5 × 27.5cm.). (Box 6)
    - 51-52. Spud Johnson., (2 poses). (Box 6)
    - 53. Looking Elk (Albert Martinez). (Box 6)
    - (2) 54-56. Gustave Bauman., (no.31-32 unmounted; various sizes). (Box 6)
    - 57. Mary Austin. (Box 6)
    - 58. Aileen Nussbaum. (Box 6)
    - 59-60. John Sloan., (no.36 unmounted, 25 × 20cm.). (Box 6)
    - (2) 61-63. Frank Hoffman. Various poses. (Box 6)
- Untitled advertisement photographs., (Mounted, 45 × 35cm.). (Box 7)
- Salon prints. Untitled views of Los Angeles and vicinity., (35 × 45cm.). (Box 7)
  - 1. Orange juice advertisement with 2 juice glasses as a backdrop, 1932. (Box 7)
  - 2. Electric juicer (Sunkist) and dolls, 1932. (Box 7)
  - 3. Three orange juice glasses and electric juicer, 1928. (Box 7)
  - 4. Man drinking orange juice (Box 7)
  - 5. Glass of juice with toy rabbit, 1928. (Box 7)
  - 6. Table setting of juice glass with bough of ranunculus, 1928. (Box 7)
  - 7. Child's place setting with juice cup and toy clown, 1928. (Box 7)
  - 8. Solitary goblet of juice, 1930. (Box 7)
  - 9. Two glasses with lemon wedges on tray, n.d. (Box 7)
  - 10. Glass with fruit slice on tray, 1929. (Box 7)
  - 11. Two glasses with lemon wedges and Sunkist lemons (Box 7)
  - 12. Two glasses with fruit wedges, n.d. (Box 7)
  - 13. Three fruit cups and bowl of fruit (Box 7)
  - 14-15. Child drinking juice, n.d.; (2 copies, no.15 shows head only). (Box 7)
  - 16. Child eating, 1931. (Box 7)
  - 17. Open bottle of Mission Day (carbonated fruit drink) and two glasses, 1920(?). (Box 7)
  - 18. Top view of Mission Day bottles showing various flavors, 1930. (Box 7)
  - 19. Bottles of Mission Day and lemons, 1930. (Box 7)
  - 20. Gingerale on tap, 1932. (Box 7)
  - 21. Scotch and Soda (Johnny Walker Red Label) (Box 7)
  - 22. Double X floor cleaner, cans froming large letter X, n.d. (Box 7)
  - 23. Floor cleaning scene, apparently Double X advertisement, 1930. (Box 7)
  - 24. Hyirs Motor Oil, 1934. (Box 7)
  - 25. Pyrol ointment, n.d. (Box 7)
  - 26. Paris Luxury perfume, 1931. (Box 7)
  - 27. Paris Luxury cosmetic products of shelves, n.d. (Box 7)
  - 28. What little girl stars are made of, Make up, wig, etc., 1938. (Box 7)
  - 29. Purse and shoe fashions, 1928. (Box 7)
  - 30. Parker Brothers games: Ping-pong, Crokay, etc., 1930. (Box 7)
  - 31. Two men in tuxedos, 1930. (Box 7)
  - 32. Man reading magazines Better Homes and Gardens, Good Housekeeping, etc.), 1937.; Cutout and mounted. (Box 7)
  - 33. Sunkist building across from Los Angeles Public Library, 1931. (Box 7)
  - 34. Bullock's Wilshire, 1932. (Box 7)
  - 35. Los Angeles view with First Congregational Church in background (Box 7)
  - 36. Mayan and Belasco Theater lights (Helen Hays in Coquette at Belasco), 1929. (Box 7)
  - 37. Downtown street scene: people waiting on corner, 1930. (Box 7)
  - 38. Downtown street scene: people crossing street, 1930. (Box 7)
  - 39. Walter Story Building, 1929. (Box 7)
  - 40. Corner street scene (West Fifth) in rain, 1930. (Box 7)
  - 41-42. Aerial view of rainy street scene at 4:15 p.m., 1930.; (no.10 slightly different placement and time, same street). (Box 7)
  - 43. Rain, Street scene at night., 1934. (Box 7)
  - 44. Study in rain, (Apparent duplicate of no.11, despite discrepancy of title and dates)., 1930. (Box 7)
  - 45. Wilshire Boulevard view through grilled window, 1933. (Box 7)
  - 46. City Hall, old cars in foreground, 1929. (Box 7)
  - 47. Los Angeles to Glendale road, south of Los Feliz, 1930. (Box 7)
  - 48. Arroyo Seco Bridge, Pasadena, California., 1933. (Box 7)
  - 49. Will Rodgers Polo field, Santa Monica, California., 1931. (Box 7)
  - 50. Los Angeles subdivision; houses sparcely scattered on hillside, 1932. (Box 7)
  - 51-55. Hollywood Bowl scenes. (Box 7)
    - 51. View of orchestra in shell, 1927. (Box 7)
    - 52. Detail of Lloyd Wright's shell, 1927. (Box 7)
    - 53. Spot Light, Spot light play on performer., 1927. (Box 7)
    - 54. View of orchestra in new shell, mountains and Hollywoodland sign in background, 1928. (Box 7)
    - 55. Hollywood Bowl audience scene, 1928. (Box 7)
  - 56-58. Special effect printing. (Box 7)
    - 56. Subdivision scene(?), n.d. (Box 7)
    - 57-58. Spot light, 1927.; (Apparent effect printing of no.21; no.26 smaller: 20 × 25cm.). (Box 7)
- Untitled salon prints. Chiefly industrial photographs; many exhibited in the Art Directors Club Show (ACS), August 1962.; (38 × 48cm., on extra-heavy mounts, 55 × 61cm.). (Box 8)
  - 1. Worker at drill-press, n.d. (Box 8)
  - 2. Man using optical instrument, n.d. (Box 8)
  - 3. Machine part, n.d. (Box 8)
  - 4. Welder, n.d. (Box 8)
  - 5. Aircraft mechanics working on airplane, n.d. (Box 8)
  - 6. Diamond (Box 8)
  - 7. Wine goblets, n.d.; (Apparent enlarged duplicate of no.17 in Box 7). (Box 8)
  - 8. Proof of the Pudding. Barr Lumber Company, Santa Ana, California., (50.5 × 61cm.). (Box 8)
  - 9. Barr Lumber Company workmen making a 5000 pound bulkhead., (50.5 × 61cm.). (Box 8)
- Salon prints, portraits of cats and dogs, some titled., Mostly mounted, 45 × 35cm, unless otherwise noted. (Box 9)
  - 1. Close-up of kitten's face, n.d.; (Unmounted, 20 × 17cm.). (Box 9)
  - 2-3. Cat playing with dice, 1929.; (2 copies; no.2, unmounted, 25 × 24cm.; no.3, 35 × 27.5cm.). (Box 9)
  - 4-5. Cat with ears laid back, 1929.; (2 copies, no.4, unmounted, 25 × 24cm.; no.5, 35 × 27.5cm.). (Box 9)
  - 6. Fluffy long-haired cat, n.d.; (Unmounted, 35 × 27.5cm.). (Box 9)
  - 7. Kitten sleeping, 1929.; (35 × 28cm.). (Box 9)
  - 8-9. Kitten starring at milk bottles, 1929.; (2 copies, no.8, unmounted, 22 × 29.5cm.; no.9, 35.5 × 28cm.). (Box 9)
  - 10-12. Patience, Cat waiting at mousehole., 1928-29.; (3 copies, various sizes and dates). (Box 9)
  - (3) 13-16. Egyptianesque, Portrait of cat's face., 1926-30.; (4 copies, various sizes and dates). (Box 9)
  - (2) 17-19. His Family Tree, Kitten posing with photo of parent., 1926.; (3 copies, various sizes). (Box 9)
  - 20. Cat snarling at another cat, 1928. (Box 9)
  - 21-23. Left profile of black and white cat, 1928-30.; (3 copies; various dates, all 29 × 24cm.). (Box 9)
  - 24. Siesta, Cat sleeping on embroidered cushion., 1927. (Box 9)
  - 25-27. Tired out, Black kitten resting with paw on ball., 1929-30.; (3 copies, various dates and sizes). (Box 9)
  - 28-30. Alley cat, 1928-29.; (3 copies, various dates, all 35 × 28cm.). (Box 9)
  - 31. Mary Q. Cat, Right profile of black and white cat., 1928. (Box 9)
  - 32. Left profile of black and white cat, (Unmounted, 35 × 28cm.). (Box 9)
  - 33. Thomas Q. Cat, Cat sitting on stairs., 1929. (Box 9)
  - (1) 34-35. Cat on foot of steps, 1929.; (2 copies, no.35 smaller: 34.5 × 28cm.). (Box 9)
  - 36. Cat lying on steps, 1928. (Box 9)
  - 37. Fluffy cat between window and iron grill, 1928. (Box 9)